Maryland Citizens Against State Executions Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Maryland Citizens Against State Executions Records 1962-2013
nam_apap340
4.9 cubic ft.
Maryland Citizens Against State Executions
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
The Maryland Citizens Against State Executions (Maryland or MD CASE) Records contain documents from over 25 groups and 1,300 individuals that united to help successfully end the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 through education, grassroots action, and public demonstration. The collection consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, legislation, lobbying materials, subject files, special event and conference materials, case files and clippings.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Jane Henderson, executive director, of Maryland Citizens Against State Executions donated all of the materials in this collection to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives in 2013.
Administrative History
Maryland Citizens Against State Executions (Maryland or MD CASE) is a coalition of over 25 groups and 1,300 individuals that united to help successfully end the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 through education, grassroots action, and public demonstration. Founded in 1997 and formally incorporated in 2000 as the Maryland Coalition Against State Executions, the group changed its name in 2003.
The decade leading to the abolishment of the death penalty in Maryland in 2013 witnessed significant activity in the debate over capital punishment in the state. In 2002 Maryland Governor Parris Glendening declared a moratorium on executions, which his successor Robert Ehrlich ended in 2004. The last state sanctioned execution occurred in 2005. In 2008, the Maryland Commission on Capital Punishment was created to study all aspects of capital punishment in the state and make recommendations regarding future use. Following completion of its study, the Commission recommended the death penalty be abolished in the state. After earlier attempts to enact similar legislation failed, both houses of the Maryland Legislature voted in favor of a bill to repeal the death penalty for future offenders in March 2013 which Governor Martin O'Malley then signed into law. As of May 2014, four men remain on Death Row in Maryland, all convicted and sentenced before 2013.
Maryland CASE was highly engaged in the debate during the years between 2003 and 2013, as evidenced by the plethora of event fliers, brochures and postcards in the collection. Today Maryland CASE remains active and is overseen by an involved board of death penalty activists. One of the alternatives to capital punishment Maryland CASE endorses is life without parole, which the organization asserts is acceptable to a majority of Maryland citizens.
The collection documents Maryland Citizens Against State Executions’ ongoing efforts to repeal capital punishment in the state. It consists of correspondence, meeting minutes, legislation, lobbying materials, subject files, special event and conference materials, case files and clippings. Much of the collection is dedicated to files on inmates, the events held to demand their release and subsequent memorial/remembrance events held after executions.
When available, the archivist retained the original file names created by Maryland CASE.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Political Outreach and Lobbying, 1962-2013, Undated
Series 2 - General/Public Outreach, 1994-2013, Undated
Series 3 - Subject Files, 1998-2013, Undated
All series are arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Death Penalty; Maryland Citizens Against State Executions; Steele, Michael S.; O'Malley, Martin; Lethal injection (Execution)--Maryland; Capital Punishment--Maryland; Legislative Hearings--Maryland; Minutes; Newsletters; Correspondence; Memorandums; Fliers (Printed matter); Postcards; Brochures; Testimonies
Container List
- Political Outreach and Lobbying, 1962-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-1; 2.0 cubic ft.
  This series contains records created by or about commissions, hearing notes, legislation, bills, testimonies, letters and other political outreach materials, collected or created by Maryland Citizens Against State Executions, intended to end the death penalty in Maryland.
  - Committee on Cap. Pun. - Report to the Legislative Council of MD, 1962; nam_apap340-1_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to/from Politicians (includes press releases and media advisories), 1978; 2001-2003; 2005; 2009; 2012; nam_apap340-1_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Court Proceedings, Testimony and Other Related Materials, 1978; 2002-2003; 2007-2009; 2011; Undated; nam_apap340-1_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Tyrone Delano Gilliam v. State of Maryland, 1989; 1992; 1994; 1998-1999; nam_apap340-1_4 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Appeals Materials, 1993; 1996; 2000; 2002-2005; 2008; nam_apap340-1_5 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - The Report of the Governor's Task Force on the Fair Imposition of Capital Punishment, 1996 December; nam_apap340-1_6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mora Bill, 1997; nam_apap340-1_7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PG County Resolutions, 2000; nam_apap340-1_8 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Moratorium Leg. B, 2000-2001; nam_apap340-1_9 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Commissions and Commission Information, 2001; 2006-2009; Undated; nam_apap340-1_10 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Research: Scholarly Articles, Statistics, Polls, Talking Points and Other Materials, 2001/2013; Undated; nam_apap340-1_11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - MD: General Assembly Materials, 2001; 2008-2009; 2011; 2013; Undated; nam_apap340-1_12 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Petitions, 2002 May 07; nam_apap340-1_13 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Achievement Award to Salima Siler Marriott, 2002 November 06; nam_apap340-1_14 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bryant, Cof. Appeals, 2002; nam_apap340-1_15 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Leg. Session, 2002; nam_apap340-1_16 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Oken Court Appeals, 2002; nam_apap340-1_17 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Opposition, 2002-2003; nam_apap340-1_18 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - MD Leg. Session, 2002-2004; Undated; nam_apap340-1_19 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Legislator Letter to Steele, 2003 June; nam_apap340-1_20 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Leg. Black Caucus, 2003; nam_apap340-1_21 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - MD Leg. Session, 2003; nam_apap340-1_22 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Schiebeir Testimony, 2003; nam_apap340-1_23 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - MD SB 744 - Comm. on Capital Punishment, 2004; nam_apap340-1_24 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - NAACP - MD Race Amicus, 2004; nam_apap340-1_25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Oken - Lethal Injection Appeal, 2004; nam_apap340-1_26 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Repeal Bill, 2004; nam_apap340-1_27 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Legislative Session, 2004-2005; Undated; nam_apap340-1_28 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Leg. Session, 2004; 2008; Undated; nam_apap340-1_29 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Record Extract - Vol. 1, 2005; nam_apap340-1_30 (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Record Extract - Vol. 2, 2005; nam_apap340-1_31 (Box 1, Folder 34-36)
  - MD PAC Info., 2005; nam_apap340-1_32 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Repeal, 2005; nam_apap340-1_33 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Commission Bill, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-1_34 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Evans v. Maryland - Brief for Appellants, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-1_35 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Proposal MD Regulations, 2005-2006; 2008-2010; nam_apap340-1_36 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Leg. Repeal Hearings, 2006; nam_apap340-1_37 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Lethal Injection (APA Civil), 2006; Undated; nam_apap340-1_38 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Resolutions, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-1_39 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Legislation Session, 2006-2007; Undated; nam_apap340-1_40 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - O'Malley Email Action, 2007 March 20; nam_apap340-1_41 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Black Caucus, Senates Letters to Governor, 2007 November; nam_apap340-1_42 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Media Advisory Packet, 2007; nam_apap340-1_43 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Miles Decision, 2007; nam_apap340-1_44 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Session MGA Letters, 2007; nam_apap340-1_45 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Venable Memos, 2007; nam_apap340-1_46 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Commission Bill, 2008 April 07; nam_apap340-1_47 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - MD Commission on Capital Punishment, 2008 July 28; nam_apap340-1_48 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Commission on Capital Punishment, 2008 August 05; nam_apap340-1_49 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Commission, 2008 August 19; nam_apap340-1_50 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Commission, 2008 September 05; nam_apap340-1_51 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Commission Hearing Testimony, 2008 September 22; nam_apap340-1_52 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Commission, 2008 October 07; nam_apap340-1_53 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Court Information and Rules, 2008 July 08; Undated; nam_apap340-1_54 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Commission on Capital Punishment Commissioner Bios, 2008; Undated; nam_apap340-1_55 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Commission Info, 2008; Undated; nam_apap340-1_56 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - MD CASE, Senate Bills, 2008-2009; Undated; nam_apap340-1_57 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Memorandum, 2009 June 04; Undated; nam_apap340-1_58 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Repeal to Reform Bill, 2009; nam_apap340-1_59 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fingerprint Evidence, 2009-2010; nam_apap340-1_60 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Materials, 2009; 2013; nam_apap340-1_61 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - MD CASE: Administrative Files, 2010; nam_apap340-1_62 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Data and Research: Figures and Tables, Undated; nam_apap340-1_63 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Hearing Notes, Undated; nam_apap340-1_64 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hunt, Flint Gregory: Memorandum and Order, Undated; nam_apap340-1_65 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Illinois Commission Analysis on Maryland, Undated; nam_apap340-1_66 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Legislative/Organizing, Undated; nam_apap340-1_67 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - MD: Capital Punishment Studies, Undated; nam_apap340-1_68 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Repeal Campaign Strategy (Strategic Map), Undated; nam_apap340-1_69 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Steele, Undated; nam_apap340-1_70 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- General/Public Outreach, 1994-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-2; 1.5 cubic ft.
  This series contains public opinion polls, event advertisements, information on related organizations (including student organizations), letters to legislators from citizens, fact sheets and other research.
  - MD CASE: Archives, 1994; 2000-2004; nam_apap340-2_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - One More Voice, 1998; nam_apap340-2_2 (Video-tape 1)
  - Baldus' Preliminary Race Analysis, 2001; nam_apap340-2_3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - MD: Sun Ad, Prominent Signer, 2001; nam_apap340-2_4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - MD Death Row Cases, 2001-2002; 2004; Undated; nam_apap340-2_5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General Outreach: Misc. Materials, 2001-2003; 2008-2010; Undated; nam_apap340-2_6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - DOJ Report on Race and Death Penalty, 2002 December 13; nam_apap340-2_7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - MD Cath. Conf., 2002; nam_apap340-2_8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MD Moratorium, 2002; nam_apap340-2_9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - MD Student Organizing, 2002-2003; nam_apap340-2_10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - PG County Organizing Contacts, 2002-2004; nam_apap340-2_11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - MD Strategy Planning, 2002-2004; Undated; nam_apap340-2_12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Race and the Death Penalty, 2002; 2004; nam_apap340-2_13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Fiscal Sponsorship, 2002; 2005-2006; nam_apap340-2_14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - MD Justice Policy Institute Study, 2003; nam_apap340-2_15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - MD COE Seminar, 2003-2004; nam_apap340-2_16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Mailings and Postcards, 2003; 2006-2009; Undated; nam_apap340-2_17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Empirical Analysis of the Imposition of the Death Penalty in Maryland, 2004; nam_apap340-2_18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - MD Students Against the Death Penalty, 2004; nam_apap340-2_19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Mount St. Mary's College, 2004; Undated; nam_apap340-2_20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - MD Crime Reports, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-2_21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - MD Editorial Packet, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-2_22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baker Execution - Mailing, 2005 November 22; nam_apap340-2_23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Begging, 2005 April; nam_apap340-2_24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Postcard - Race/Oral Argument, 2005 June; nam_apap340-2_25 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bonnita, 2005; nam_apap340-2_26 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Duncan, 2005; nam_apap340-2_27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Helen Prejean Visit, 2005; nam_apap340-2_28 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Mailing Appeal, 2005; nam_apap340-2_29 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Polling-MD, 2005; nam_apap340-2_30 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Hell Week Originals, 2005; Undated; nam_apap340-2_31 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - MD CASE Packet, 2005; Undated; nam_apap340-2_32 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Afro American Ad, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-2_33 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - OMW Opera, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-2_34 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Press Releases and Newspapers, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-2_35 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Mont. Co. Citizens of Faith, 2005-2006; 2008; nam_apap340-2_36 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Brochures and Magazines, 2005-2006; 2009; 2011-2012; nam_apap340-2_37 (Box 1, Folder 36-37)
  - Ask Ehrlich and Steele, 2006; nam_apap340-2_38 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Death Penalty Information Center, 2006; nam_apap340-2_39 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - From the Death House to the Courthouse, 2006; nam_apap340-2_40 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Member Organization (CASE), 2006; nam_apap340-2_41 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Press Releases, 2006; nam_apap340-2_42 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Witness and Action, 2006; nam_apap340-2_43 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Witness and Action: Christian Responses to the Death Penalty, 2006; nam_apap340-2_44 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Board of Directors Information, Charts, Notes and Other Materials, 2006; Undated; nam_apap340-2_45 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Annapolis U.U. Church, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-2_46 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Archived Newsletters, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-2_47 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "In Her Honor" Memorial Information, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-2_48 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - LTE's, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-2_49 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Maryland Commission on Capital Punishment: Findings and Recommendation, 2006; 2011; Undated; nam_apap340-2_50 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Newsletters, 2006-2012; nam_apap340-2_51 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Maryland Catholic Conference, 2007 April 04; nam_apap340-2_52 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Active Voice/RTE Screening, 2007; nam_apap340-2_53 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Ads, 2007; nam_apap340-2_54 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Beyond the Bottom Line, 2007; nam_apap340-2_55 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Frederick-In the Streets, 2007; nam_apap340-2_56 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Institute for Race and Justice Materials, 2007; nam_apap340-2_57 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Legislative Packets, 2007; nam_apap340-2_58 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - MGA Religious Sign On, 2007; nam_apap340-2_59 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Mailing Archives, 2007; nam_apap340-2_60 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Post: "A Governor Stands Up", 2007; nam_apap340-2_61 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Reggie Lewis Event, 2007; nam_apap340-2_62 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Strategy Stuff, 2007; nam_apap340-2_63 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Sun: "End the Death Penalty", 2007; nam_apap340-2_64 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Takoma Park Street Fest., 2007; nam_apap340-2_65 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - University of Baltimore Law Forum, 2007; nam_apap340-2_66 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Amnesty Int., 2007; Undated; nam_apap340-2_67 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - MD Polling, 2007; Undated; nam_apap340-2_68 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Polling (District), 2007; 2009; nam_apap340-2_69 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - At the Death House Door, 2008; nam_apap340-2_70 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - EJUSA Files, 2008; nam_apap340-2_71 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - MD Fundraising Files, 2008; nam_apap340-2_72 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Progressive Summit, 2008; nam_apap340-2_73 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Repeal Nights-Camden Yards, 2008; nam_apap340-2_74 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - State Death Penalty Abolition Coordinator: Resource Manual, 2008; nam_apap340-2_75 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Urban Institute Study & 2008 Report on the MD Committee on Capital Punishment, nam_apap340-2_76 (Cd 1)
  - Hood College Community Service Fair, 2008/2009; nam_apap340-2_77 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - "The Cost of the Death Penalty" and Other Materials, 2008; 2011; Undated; nam_apap340-2_78 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Resolutions, Articles and Other Materials, 2008-2013; nam_apap340-2_79 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - "Voices of Change: Death Penalty Repeal" Poster, 2009 February 12; nam_apap340-2_80 (Flat-file 1)
  - Death Penalty, 2009 February 24; nam_apap340-2_81 (Cd 2)
  - "At the Death House Door": Snack Voucher, 2009 March; nam_apap340-2_82 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Communications, 2009-2010; nam_apap340-2_83 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Fact Sheet Originals, 2009; 2011; Undated; nam_apap340-2_84 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Events, 2009; 2011-2012; Undated; nam_apap340-2_85 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Polls, 2010; nam_apap340-2_86 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Campaign, 2011; nam_apap340-2_87 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - LI-Berkley "Comments" (water damaged), 2011; nam_apap340-2_88 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - NCADP, 2011; nam_apap340-2_89 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - MD Fact Sheets and Other Materials, 2011; Undated; nam_apap340-2_90 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Fliers & Informative Posters, 2011-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-2_91 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Pamphlets, Fliers & Other Materials, 2011-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-2_92 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - State Voices, 2012; nam_apap340-2_93 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Ad Rate Cards, Undated; nam_apap340-2_94 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - An Empirical Analysis of MD's Death Sentencing System, Undated; nam_apap340-2_95 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Brochures, Undated; nam_apap340-2_96 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - The Case for Repeal, Undated; nam_apap340-2_97 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Cath. Con. Poll, Undated; nam_apap340-2_98 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Executions Create More Victims, Undated; nam_apap340-2_99 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Fair and Equal Under the Law?, Undated; nam_apap340-2_100 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Faith-Based Res, Undated; nam_apap340-2_101 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Fliers, Undated; nam_apap340-2_102 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - FPC Lifenet Legal Defense Campaign Event - Play I, Undated; nam_apap340-2_103 (Cd 3)
  - Home Partner, Undated; nam_apap340-2_104 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - How to Get Your Res Passed, Undated; nam_apap340-2_105 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Impact on Victims, Undated; nam_apap340-2_106 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Innocent Lives in the Balance", Undated; nam_apap340-2_107 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Invitations to Fundraisers, Undated; nam_apap340-2_108 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Law Enforcement Letter, Undated; nam_apap340-2_109 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Lobby Night, Undated; nam_apap340-2_110 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - MD CASE/The Abell Foundation Packet, Undated; nam_apap340-2_111 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - MD Citizens Against State Executions packet, Undated; nam_apap340-2_112 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Proposal MD Regulations, Undated; nam_apap340-2_113 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Old Fact Sheets, Undated; nam_apap340-2_114 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Old Letterhead, Undated; nam_apap340-2_115 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Opera Postcard, Undated; nam_apap340-2_116 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - OSI - Bonnita Stuff, Undated; nam_apap340-2_117 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Postcards/Fliers, Undated; nam_apap340-2_118 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Postcards to Officials, Undated; nam_apap340-2_119 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Resolution for Repeal, Undated; nam_apap340-2_120 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Signed Letters Requesting End of DP, Undated; nam_apap340-2_121 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Speech Notes, Undated; nam_apap340-2_122 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stopmax Conference FPC - Workshop Session, Undated; nam_apap340-2_123 (Cd 4)
  - Victims' Letters, Undated; nam_apap340-2_124 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wasteful and Expensive, Undated; nam_apap340-2_125 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Subject Files, 1998-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-3; 1.4 cubic ft.
  This series contains a diverse collection of material from or associated with Maryland Citizens Against State Executions. The files contain research, articles, inmate files, legislator files, politician files, press materials, analysis, and reports.
  - MRJ, 1998; nam_apap340-3_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Collins, Kenneth, 2000; nam_apap340-3_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Borchart Court Appeals, 2000-2001; 2005-2006; nam_apap340-3_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 2000-2001; 2003-2005; 2007; 2009; nam_apap340-3_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - MD: CASE - General Clippings About the Death Penalty, 2000-2013; Undated; nam_apap340-3_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Background on MD CASE, 2000; 2008; 2010; nam_apap340-3_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - MD Media: Articles & OPed's, 2001-2002; 2005; nam_apap340-3_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - MD CASE: Research & Correspondence, 2001-2003; 2006; 2008-2009; 2012; nam_apap340-3_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Oken Sign-On Letter, 2001-2004; Undated; nam_apap340-3_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Articles, 2001; 2005; 2013; nam_apap340-3_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper: Gazette/Voters Guide, 2002 August 29; nam_apap340-3_11 (Flat-file 2)
  - Baltimore Co., 2002; nam_apap340-3_12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Glen Ivey, 2002; nam_apap340-3_13 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - MD - Post Moratorium Coverage, 2002; nam_apap340-3_14 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oken - Care Facts Summary, 2002; nam_apap340-3_15 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Logan Care - PG Co., 2002-2003; nam_apap340-3_16 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Opposition Research, 2002-2003; nam_apap340-3_17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Washington Sniper", 2002-2003; nam_apap340-3_18 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Wiggins, 2002-2003; nam_apap340-3_19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Printed Online Newspaper Articles, 2002-2003; 2008; 2012; nam_apap340-3_20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - DNA Innocence Newspaper Articles, 2002-2004; nam_apap340-3_21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Media, 2003 June; nam_apap340-3_22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Conover Case, 2003; nam_apap340-3_23 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Curran, A G Joe, 2003; nam_apap340-3_24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - DNA, Innocence (Supplemental), 2003; nam_apap340-3_25 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Kirk Bloodsworth, 2003; nam_apap340-3_26 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Maryland State Attorneys, 2003; nam_apap340-3_27 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - PG Co. Minister, 2003; nam_apap340-3_28 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Oken, More About, 2003-2004; nam_apap340-3_29 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Steele, Lt. Gov., 2003-2004; nam_apap340-3_30 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Webster Care (and Resulting Fallout Out), 2003; 2005; nam_apap340-3_31 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Abeokuta, Jamaal, 2004; nam_apap340-3_32 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Burch Case, 2004; nam_apap340-3_33 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Legal Issues, 2004; nam_apap340-3_34 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - MD Balt. Co. Police Officer (Monty Smith), 2004; nam_apap340-3_35 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - MD CASE Minutes, 2004; nam_apap340-3_36 (Cd 5)
  - Oken Press Coverage - June 2004 Execution Date, nam_apap340-3_37 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Evans, Vernon, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-3_38 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - MD CASE: Board Materials, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-3_39 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Race Appeal, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-3_40 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Wesley Baker, 2004-2005; nam_apap340-3_41 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Old News Clippings, 2004-2007; 2009; 2011; nam_apap340-3_42 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - MD CASE Minutes, 2005; nam_apap340-3_43 (Cd 6)
  - Baker & Evans Media, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-3_44 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - PG Co. Articles, 2005-2006; nam_apap340-3_45 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Corrections, 2005-2007; nam_apap340-3_46 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - The Sun: Articles, 2006 November 06; nam_apap340-3_47 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Board and Executive Committee Meeting Notes, 2006; nam_apap340-3_48 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - UMD Study, 2006; Undated; nam_apap340-3_49 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Baltimore City, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-3_50 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Press Archives - Bill, 2006-2007; nam_apap340-3_51 (Box 1, Folder 48)